jwgray4@hotmail.com

### **SUM MARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

A highly driven and analytical public finance professional with years of debt management and operating/capital budgeting experience who pairs strong collaboration skills to effectively manage diverse workforces and motivate team members to achieve its organizational mission and meet customer and constituent needs. Leverages strong leadership and communication abilities to mentor and facilitate the advancement of others. Evaluates existing processes, identifies opportunities for enhancement, and implements changes for the greater good of the organization.

Skills include - Microsoft Office; ERP systems (PeopleSoft); Debt Management - DBC and MunEase

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Debt Administrator

## July 2015 to present

City of San José

- Manage City's \$4.7 billion debt portfolio, including the administration/management of debt issuance and debt related projects; provide financial analysis to City departments; frequent creator/contributor to Council Memos for debt related items;
- Key Financings include: Airport \$620 million and SARA \$1.7 billion, both refundings; GO Measure T \$500 million;
- Annual Reporting Requirements Comprehensive Debt Report; MSRB Disclosure; Trustees Compliance; State Treasurer Reports;
- Quarterly Debt Reports to City Council;
- Manage City's Credit Rating Agency Relations and Maintenance;
- Dissolution of the San Jose Redevelopment Agency;
- Supervise, manage and train a debt management staff of four, providing plenty of "hands on" contribution; and
- Received the City's Pride of San José award in 2018 and 2019 as recognition for exceptional team work and project accomplishments.

#### Consultant

# April 2013 to July 2015

YADARI Enterprises

• Primary responsibilities include: public sector consulting; new business development and public outreach for public sector accounts; provide strategic planning and direction for government procurement and IT system applications.

### Finance Director

# October 2011 to April 2013

City of Napa

- Dissolution of the Napa Redevelopment Agency;
- Banking Services RFP service improvement;
- Quarterly Financial presentations to Mayor/Council;
- Reconfigured accounting section to improve cross-training;
- Conducted audit of TOT revenues improved collections 100% for those audits;
- Development of the City's Operating Budget (\$60m General Fund and \$150m All Funds);
- Budget Update presentations to labor groups during labor negotiations; and
- Supervised staff of 35 (Financial Reporting; Accounts Payable & Receivable; Treasury; Debt Issuance; IT; Payroll; Utility Billing).

#### Finance Director

#### October 2009 to October 2011

City of Fresno

- Improved Business License process audit/improvement of Business License procedures, its database and geographical locators for use by other city departments; implemented on-line payment/renewal solution; increased collections of A/R by 25%;
- Implemented new utility software solution (HTE/SunGard, DIVDAT and Progressive Solutions) that improved data management/integration and operational efficiencies and allow for a complete overhaul of the City's water billing methodology;
- Issued \$158 million in Water Revenue Bonds (\$91m of which was the City's first Build America Bonds);
- Issued \$46.5 million of private placement financing for Museum / Park Facilities;
- Issued \$58 million TRANs issuance;
- Healthy annual financial reports (CAFR);
- Rating Agency presentations;
- Treasury cash/investment management; and
- Supervised staff of 120 (Financial Reporting; Accounts Payable & Receivable; Treasury; Debt Issuance, Payroll; Utility Billing).

City of Cincinnati

Asst. Finance Director

- May 2004 to January 2006
- Provide annual revenue estimates for the City's operating budget (\$370 million) and capital budget (\$65 million);
- Bond issuance for capital and economic development financing \$100 million to \$200 million annually (including the City's first use of Build America Bonds and Recovery Zone Bonds); Water Utility Refunding \$8 million in savings;
- Rating Agency presentations;
- Financial model for Kroger Parking garage project;
- Treasury cash/investment management; and
- Supervised staff of 130 (Accounts & Audits; Treasury; Internal Audit; Purchasing, Retirement, Taxation and Risk Management).

### Debt Analyst

1988 to 2004

Ohio Office of Budget & Management

- Debt Management of \$1 billion annual issuance;
- Provided analysis of various municipal financings new money, refundings, derivative products; certificates of participation, RFP's; bond/debt sizing and structure;
- Rating Agency presentations;
- Budget Analyst for various agencies (Adult and Juvenile Corrections, Public Defender, Criminal Justice, Historical Society, Governor's Office, and State and Local Government Commission); and
- OBM representative/chairman on all state declared Financial Planning and Supervision Commissions formed to oversee municipalities declared in fiscal emergency by the Auditor of State.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.A., Finance The Ohio State University Columbus, Ohio